THE SADIDA TEMPLE
Here we are, at last,
after all these years.
My friends, we're nearing our goal!
-You don't have any doubts?
-No, but do you?
We're going for the gods.
Only a madman wouldn't.
Will they surrender?
You have the Eliatrope Dofus
and I have the Eliacube Adamai.
They're not powerful with these weapons.
The most powerful, Goultard,
was defeated easily.
He wasn't the real Iop god!
You can doubt many things,
but never doubt our cause.
It's time to give this universe
gods it deserves.
A gambler, an underwear collector,
a psychopath, and children.
Some of your demigods
won't do much better.
-We'll watch them carefully.
-Yeah right!
We know what you're capable of.
Nobody would dream of defying you.
Tell me, my handsome dragon,
I suppose I'm the psychopath.
Know any others?
No!
Why are you here, Toxine?
Evangelyne and her kid have escaped.
They must be on the Cra level.
How did they escape my temple?
If you spent more time there instead
of flirting with Oropo, you'd know.
You!
Stop acting like children.
Go find them and bring them to me.
You get so worked up these days,
you seem troubled.
Do me a favor and shut up.
Is this necessary? You've changed
since the brotherhood arrived.
You're right. Their presence reminds me
of my non-existence, of who I'm not.
But you can still have faith in me,
I won't fail.
Wow! Looks like a training room.
This is the Cra level. Be cautious.
Mama, it looks like your bow.
It was destroyed when Adamai attacked.
You're right. That is my bow.
It's okay, darling,
just the baby sending signals.
We need to get out and find your father.
I promise I won't let anyone hurt you,
or the baby.
I know you won't. Help me.
Let's find a way out.
That way. Don't waste time.
Okay, shouldn't we take weapons,
just in case?
Quickly. I have a bad feeling.
Oh?
The rats are leaving the ship.
Is... this a dream?
I'm having the same one.
We're in a tower. How are we in a field?
We must be on Sadida level. Feel anything?
Was talking about you and Amalia.
I'm not sure if what I feel is love.
I'm not ready for it.
-I feel like I'll live forever.
-Have you talked to Amalia?
Yes and no. I tried but I can't get
a word in with that princess.
Sometimes she's so self-absorbed.
I feel a lot of sadness, Yugo,
but it's not from here.
Right.
I can't seem to communicate
with the plants.
No, I don't feel a single thing.
Maybe not a good idea.
Greetings, Brotherhood of Tofu.
Oropo, master of this tower,
told me of your coming.
I've been looking forward to this.
Follow, my dolls.
They will lead you to me.
It's not like
we had anything better to do.
Grandpa Ruel is less scared than usual.
The first time being called Grandpa
didn't bother you!
People get used to things, Elely.
Be on guard.
This place isn't what it seems.
There's no life in the plants.
Amalia, you seem upset.
Women are complicated, aren't they?
Complicated and troubling.
-Aren't you overdoing it, Amalia?
-Such a fake friend!
I heard what you said to Yugo on Enutrof.
You think I'm self-absorbed
and can't see when others are in pain.
That's what Yugo said.
And you don't think the same?
-About you? I think much worse.
-What?
Look at yourself. You're always acting
like an obnoxious princess.
You treat your friends like servants.
After everything we've been through,
how dare you?
Yugo is like my son.
I don't know what he sees in you.
You're making him suffer when he needs
to concentrate on more important things.
Please, I'll do whatever you want,
but let me go.
You're my husband, Ruel,
for better or worse.
Though there were more worse with you.
I gave you everything, Ruel.
Everything I had and you? You ran away!
I'm sorry for it all,
I know I made a mistake.
A mistake? That's one way to put it.
There I was imagining a family,
a bunch of little Enutrofs.
They cost a lot, though.
You're not funny!
Thanks to Oropo,
we'll make up for lost time.
He's making you a god.
This is ridiculous!
Don't tell me you believe it!
Of course I do, you fool!
Would I go to all this trouble, if not?
After your betrayal, I was broken.
I wasted years of my life crying,
until Oropo made me a deal.
To make me into a god.
We'll finally be together, Ruel.
We'll be rich. We'll have it all.
Arpagone...
Don't push me away again, Ruel.
I love you.
With your beautiful bare scalp
and wrinkles and three remaining teeth.
No, but...
I'm crazy about you, Ruel.
Don't push me away.
-Did you think the door was just for dogs?
-Tell us how to get to the next level!
Of course. It'll cost your undies.
That's two more pairs.
-Quicker to have smashed his teeth in.
-You should be proud of me.
I was trying to think like Yugo.
He'd have preferred this to a fight.
If you say so...
Oh! Aren't they just adorable
with their little bows?
Silence, Toxine, don't poison things.
Poisoning is what I do best.
I told you, we mean you no harm.
Oropo has big plans for your kids.
And I told you no!
Our mission is more important, Evangelyne.
Look around. It was designed for Flopin.
He'll be a perfect Cra god.
Do you understand
what we're offering them?
You can't decide their future.
Unfortunately, it is for the greater good.
They're children of a god and ideal
to replace the imbeciles that rule us.
We want you to join us.
I promise you won't...
You... You...
You should have let me handle this.
We don't always agree
on how the brotherhood should act.
Toxine, what are you...
-Save your strength. You'll need it.
-Stay behind me, Flopin.
I've disliked your arrogance
for quite a while.
Pining over the handsome Oropo,
while others do the dirty work.
Unlike everyone else, I know who I am.
I despise stuck-up people,
who think they're better than others.
And you, blondie,
that definitely includes you.
So, I can't resist the urge
to teach you a lesson.
You are completely insane.
Oropo will never forgive you.
Yes, he will. He chose me
as the future Sram goddess.
He must have known
I'd stab him in the back.
Anyway, who says he'll find out?
Behind me, Mama!
Finally, someone who understands me.
Look at yourself.
Nearly there.
I am Dathura and you're in my domain.
One of the dolls of the Sadida god.
I haven't been out in a long time.
It surprises me that you know me.
Interesting, but we're not here
for a plant history lesson.
I guess there's a test
before we can move up.
Sorry to disappoint, Elely,
but I don't engage in those games.
I simply wish to talk to you a while.
First, I want to know
how my little Ogrest is.
I heard you took the Dofus from him.
He's okay, with his father, Otomai.
Do you know him?
I am responsible for what happened to him.
I've always regretted my actions.
It's true?
Ogrest nearly destroyed
the World of Twelve,
as he thought you were dead.
Every evolution requires sacrifice.
However, I feel so guilty.
So, I will tell you
what Oropo plans to do.
Maybe you'll understand why I'm helping.
We don't have the time
and what if she's lying?
You? How dare you?
Ruel!
Nothing but a baby.
Do you think you can take me?
No, but my mother has already
defeated you before.
She can do it again.
I underestimated you two before.
That won't happen again.
-I missed her.
-It happens.
Not to sound conceited, but... not to me.
Flopin, no!
Leave him alone, you psychopath!
I don't really know why I hate you.
Don't take it personally. I hate everyone.
I can't help it.
Impossible! That never happens to me.
She's trapped us.
We're not in the Cra temple now.
Oh, bad girl!
If you explain all my tricks,
we can't stay friends.
It's all fake, even the arrows.
Of course, how stupid of me.
They're useless. Toxine tricked us.
I know, but I have an idea.
We can still find a use.
-What are you doing?
-The traps are real.
I can make a real weapon
if I combine them.
My dear, I wanted to wait,
but you're ruining my fun.
-Have you heard of my well of shadows?
-No, not that...!
Oh, that's right. I've already told you.
Nobody ever returns.
Honestly, I don't know what's there.
A representation of my soul--
Stop, Toxine! You can't do this to me!
I know it's very cruel...
but I just can't help it.
Flopin, whatever you're doing,
do it quickly!
Almost done... Almost!
I know how this works, Echo.
In this dimension Oropo has created,
we can do anything.
Our stages are a reflection
of what we are.
But if we can't play with them,
what good are they?
Remember what I taught you, sweetie.
Oh, my, still so full of hope.
Mama... the smoke... It's...
Does it make you cry? Poor thing.
Impressive!
You're doing well,
but you've already lost.
You're in my home, after all!
Flopin!
That was fun, but playtime is over now!
Flopin, get down!
Little vermin! You'll pay for that!
You!
Perper...
I felt it, too. It's... It's Eva.
Something's happened to her.